hi i'm jodh singh
i'm currently working at what fix uh as
a associate product manager and before
that i actually i had a
four years of experience mainly in cost
consulting
corporate sales and an internship in
product management
and i am a graduate from punjab
engineering college and i have done my
mba from ayam udaipur so that's all
about my professional and academic
experience that i have
i was working as a product intern at icc
lombard where my
project was to
increase the retention for one of their
products
so
i i like managed different stakeholders
i got to interact with lot of different
uh teams within the company also i had a
chance to get uh and interact with
customers after that
i realized that as working as a product
manager uh i got to
be a part of any product journey right
from inception of the idea towards the
implementation so i was involved in a
lot of different phases i took a couple
of electives during my mba as well to
gain a little more knowledge about it
basically i believe they are the three
things that worked for me the first one
was as i mentioned that you get to
interact with a lot of different
stakeholders and you are involved in a
lot of different stages so you have that
opportunity to network with lot of
people
and to interact with people like i
really enjoy interacting with people
having different perspectives so that
really worked for me the second point i
believe is
as you are involved from right from the
ideation towards the implementation part
so you get to act as a protagonist in a
lot of different phases and which makes
me more involved with in the uh with the
product and that's what i loved about
product management and third and the
most important i feel is for any job um
role i believe there should be a
continuous learning that should be
happening on the way and given the fact
uh
the kind of technology changes we are
having also the customers how they are
um
changing their behaviors or their needs
so there's a always there's a continuous
learning process that is happening along
the job so that is that's what final
factor that was the final factor that
motivated me or encouraged me to pursue
my career in this field
first thing was what is the uh what are
the topics or what are the things i need
to cover while preparing for product
management while studying for product
management field the second challenge
was that i need to focus on where do i
get this resources from where should i
study whether i could i should go for
any
blogs or youtube videos or maybe read a
book something like that so i was not
clear about where to start that and
third was
i i
during my research i realized that the
the process the interview process and
how companies hire for these roles it's
quite different
so
the next challenge was where to do my
interview preparation whom to talk to
who are the relevant people i could talk
to and if there is any possibility i
could give a mock or i could receive a
feedback on my answer that might i might
have prepared for any of the product
design or metric or any kind of that
question so that was the three major
challenge i challenges i faced
before coming to appraise
so the case test that i gave kind of
test that it was it was not a general
general aptitude test it had a lot of
cases as well and how do you
do a lot of inference thinking that was
a completely different experience than
what i had in the past so that was and
the report that i got and you have a
score and then there's a
there's a map or there's a chart which
shows that what are the areas you're
lacking in
so that was quite interesting take uh
for uh like on my performance so that
was also interesting but i got to
realize that these are the major things
i need to focus on i need to work on
so uh before starting even the praise
journey i was aware about the fact that
these are the areas that i need to put
more focus on and these are the areas
i'm good at i might use it
while my during my interviews or during
my preparation i was working at that
time i was a working professional so i
had uh not that much time to spare
during my time and the way the gradual
learning process that happened it really
helped me so the first one was that it
was a gradual program and there was a
lot of phases that were happening
uh secondly if i talk about um
[Music]
so it got me introduced to from uh quite
basic of what product manager does
towards a lot of a little bit of
technical know-how also uh was present
in that uh course actually upskilled my
knowledge about
what is happening and what are the
things that i need to know before
entering this field and the third if i
talk about there was a lot of interviews
that were happening
so even be it peer-to-peer beat expert
interview so that was really give me
good understanding
and a good exposure how the interviews
go like
you